<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essays on HINGED</title>
    <link>https://hinged.blog/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essays on HINGED</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hinged.blog/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Ink</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#electronic-ink</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#electronic-ink</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At midnight on July 15th 2005, thousands of people were queueing to get their hands on a hardback copy of Harry Potter &amp;amp; The Half-Blood Prince. I sat at home and waited. Taking advantage of time-zones, a worldwide army of volunteers coordinated a massive transcription effort and released it as an ebook, which I read in my Palm PDA the next morning. That was my first experience of reading fiction electronically, and while imperfect, it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I didn’t know at the time was that a year earlier Sony had released the first commercial electronic book reader in Japan, called the Librie. I ordered one in January 2006 after reading an &lt;a href=&#34;https://boingboing.net/2004/07/02/sonys-librie-ebook-r.html&#34;&gt;article on BoingBoing&lt;/a&gt;. It was my first international purchase, a fact that I remember because I was terrified that it wouldn’t arrive and that I’d be out of pocket by five hundred quid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been a couple of electronic devices in my lifetime that have been so unlike anything released before that they elicit genuine amazement. The iPod touch was one. The Librie was another. It was the first example of an e-ink screen, which was low resolution by today’s standards, but quite remarkable back then. The software was in Japanese, though there was a hack to turn bits of it to English, and it was slow — but I didn’t pick up a paper book the whole time I owned it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/sony-librie.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;My Sony Librie&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;My Sony Librie&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve owned tons of e-ink devices since then. Sony and Amazon ruled the market for a while, but there’s now a plethora of companies doing interesting things with e-ink. Boox, Kobo and Pocketbook make e-readers that leave the Kindle in the dust, and companies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://supernote.com.cn&#34;&gt;Supernote&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://remarkable.com&#34;&gt;Remarkable&lt;/a&gt; are making some compelling note-taking devices with the larger screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about e-ink as a display technology is its limitations. It doesn’t do colour, and the refresh rate is abysmal - so the only thing it’s any good for is displaying single pages of information. It’s the one piece of technology that I own that acts as an antidote to all the other technology I own. There are no ads, and no tracking. No infinite scroll or notifications. It does one thing only: let me escape this world for other worlds, uninterrupted - at least for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Everything Store</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#the-everything-store</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#the-everything-store</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I find people like Jeff Bezos fascinating, and not just because they are fabulously wealthy and have more boats than me (for the record, I have none). I would be a rubbish CEO. I can barely drag myself out of bed in the morning. I have the drive and ambition of a lumbering tortoise. How do you build and manage a company of the size and complexity of Amazon? How do you grow it from selling a few books on the internet to what it is now? Think of how many moving parts there are in a company of this size. It’s mind boggling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine going back in time and trying to explain Amazon to someone in the pre-internet days. A store with no shops, that you browse with a computer (let’s not bamboozle them with smartphones just yet), that sells basically &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; and will deliver it to your house in under twenty-four hours. Younger me would think that older me is suffering from a degenerative brain condition.Amazon gets a lot of stick, and so does Jeff Bezos. Amazon has changed how we shop, to the detriment of our high streets, local stores and small businesses. It is a sprawling empire with a market capitalisation larger than the GDP of most countries, employing over a million people. It has its own fleet of aeroplanes and a logistics operation that will soon be bigger than Fedex and UPS. It runs the servers that power most of the internet and will be at the forefront of our experiments with AI in the future. Meanwhile, Jeff Bezos became one of the richest people on the planet, and &lt;em&gt;nobody&lt;/em&gt; likes rich people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it good that a single company holds so much power? On balance, probably.. not? The regulators will have their say on that. I’d say it’s fairly likely that US regulators will force them to spin off their cloud computing platform, AWS. And Amazon’s aversion to paying its fair share of tax will eventually be reconciled. Even so, it’s hard to see anything slowing it down significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would have always been an Amazon of some sort. It’s a natural result of globalisation, capitalism and the internet. Bezos had an idea, implemented it before anyone else - did it better than anyone else - and relentlessly drove it forward into the biggest retail operation on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you think of the company, or the person, it’s one hell of an achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an addendum, it’s often said that money doesn’t make you happy. I think this is bullshit. I would be deliriously happy with a couple of billion in the bank. But putting that to one side for a moment, let me be trivial and remark upon the physical transformation of Jeff Bezos. You’d probably win a fight with Jeff Bezos in 1998, but 2017 Jeff Bezos could rappel out of a helicopter, chase you for ten miles and &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; kick your ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/DE0j0DbU0AAc4Q1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting my shed to an office</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#converting-my-shed-to-an-office</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#converting-my-shed-to-an-office</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The justification for this tale of folly is that my wife and I are home-working, me permanently and my wife for the next couple of months at least. We don&amp;rsquo;t have enough room in the house for a dedicated space. The closest we have is the conservatory, but for at least half the day it bakes you alive. What we do have is a shed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our shed is the standard sized timber-framed thing that you’ll find at the bottom of most British gardens. It’s about ten years old, but has been looked after. I reckoned that I could turn it into a useable office space without much fuss. An article in The Times says that these conversions are known as a &amp;lsquo;shoffice&amp;rsquo; - an amalgamation of shed &amp;amp; office. I am never going to call it that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone famous once said that the best place to start is the beginning. I trundled down to see what my starting point was, then lay down on the floor, curled myself into the fetal position and sobbed quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0560-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Messy shed&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any good shed, it&amp;rsquo;s rammed with junk - but a casual survey suggests that the structure is basically sound. The main faults are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a minor leak on the roof&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a small hole where a mouse has broken in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some water penetration on the walls where the shiplap has deterioriated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can fix that. The game is on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-preparation&#34;&gt;Step 1: Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured that I have enough knowledge about the fundamentals of building construction to take on a project like this - because I live in a house, and how hard can it be? But I would need some sort of plan, if only to reassure other people that I knew what I was doing. The first step was to commission some detailed technical drawings of the structure and dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/shed-planning.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that done, I needed to clear all the junk out. This was a real pain. I decided to dump it in a big pile in the garden. Meanwhile, a significant amount of building materials are piling up in our hallway, increasing the risk that I might have to live in the shed rather than work in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-fix-the-roof&#34;&gt;Step 1: Fix the roof&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old felt on the roof was brittle and porous. I replaced it with some brand-spanking-new long-life roofing felt. It would have been easier if I had bought the right amount of felt, saving me an additional trip to Wickes in the middle of a global pandemic, but the actual work was straight-forward, and I am at least 90% confident that it is water-tight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost of materials: Approximately £60&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-add-some-windows&#34;&gt;Step 2: Add some windows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My shed didn&amp;rsquo;t have any windows. Sitting in the dark didn&amp;rsquo;t sound much fun, so I ordered two panes of UPVC glazing from a local glass factory. At this point I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how I was going to install the glass - so I put that little worry aside for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day came and I started worrying about how I was going to install the glass. The basic plan I came up with was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a timber frame on the inside to support the weight of the glass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut out two holes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make external and internal framing to hold the glass in place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting the holes in the shed was terrifying, because from that point on it’s no longer a good shed - it’s just a shit building with holes in it. Anyway, after much swearing, cutting and hammering I ended up with two framed holes that looked approximately like windows. In my humble but expert opinion, a good window has two desirable features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can see out of it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn’t let the outside weather inside&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give myself full marks for the first one. The second one is more difficult. There is a technical term we use at work - &amp;lsquo;silicone-the-shit-out-of-it&amp;rsquo; - which translates roughly to fixing something by applying lots and lots of silicone sealant. I installed the glass, framed it, applied lots of silicone and crossed my fingers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0571-1-1024x516.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Building the exterior frames&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to replace the rotten sections of cladding with bits removed for the windows - a stroke of good luck rather than good planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost for glass: £28&lt;br&gt;
Cost for other materials: £20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-insulation-and-boarding&#34;&gt;Step 3: Insulation and Boarding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sheds tend to be a bit cold in the winter, so I insulated the walls and ceiling with 20mm polystyrene sheets and then added a layer of thick polythene to keep moisture out. Polystyrene is awful to work with, but cheap and easy for a weakling like me to carry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted finished walls, so plasterboard is realistically the only option for the inside. I can’t skim so the plan is to board it, fill the gaps, slap some paint on and hope for the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/shed-insulation.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step was time-consuming. Because of the small space, each piece of insulation and plasterboard has to be individually cut to size. I asked a friend help me with the boarding - but he’s the annoying sort that insists that I will only learn if I do things myself, so I didn’t save as much time as much as I had hoped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the boards now installed, I filled the gaps with filler, left it to dry and sanded the joints down to create what I hoped (but wasn&amp;rsquo;t) a smooth finish. I also moved the small consumer unit to a better location and reinstalled the light. It&amp;rsquo;s now beginning to look less like a shed and more like a room. I feel like Tim Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0573-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0574-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: approx £210 (less approx £100 of donated materials)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-4-finishing-off&#34;&gt;Step 4: Finishing off&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am relatively happy with myself again by the time I&amp;rsquo;ve finished painting, and the paint has taken to the plasterboard better than I expected. I built a desk and some storage out of CLS timber &amp;amp; plywood, laid down some laminate, installed some skirting, two double sockets, some blinds and called it a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how it looked on the last day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0616.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a minor technical hitch when I realised that my WiFi doesn’t reach the end of the garden. Well, it does and it doesn’t. Download speeds were great, but upload non-existent. That wouldn’t have bothered me a year ago, but you need a decent amount of upload bandwidth for video calls. I tried Powerline adaptors. They worked, but only at 6mbps (probably because of the distance and the number of circuits). I wasn’t having that when I’ve got a 200mbps connection in the house, so I ran an ethernet cable in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0619-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve had some bad weather over the past week, and no leaks. I&amp;rsquo;m calling it watertight and declaring mission accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS makes the web tolerable again</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#rss-makes-the-web-tolerable-again</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#rss-makes-the-web-tolerable-again</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in the halcyon days of the early web the large internet portals, like Netscape, Yahoo and AOL, were starting to think about how their customers would access the ever-growing amount of content being produced on the internet. The answer they came up with was ‘syndication’. From the user perspective this was as simple as adding a BBC News or Wired widget on your homepage. If you are as old as me you might even remember doing it. Behind the scenes these content transactions were powered by a syndication protocol called RSS (which stands for ‘Really Simple Syndication’ or ‘Rich Site Summary’, depending on who you ask). Theoretically this was good for everyone: content providers were able to to reach people they would never have reached before, users had control over how and where they receive content, and the portals kept customers on their sites for longer by offering personalised experiences, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/mynetscape.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while RSS was ubiquitous, but it faltered when the larger social networks became the main vehicle of syndicated content - and it didn’t help that it has never been particularly user-friendly. Most people now get their news from social media but recent years have shown that this can be problematic: social media platforms are not neutral content providers. They manipulate how, when and what content is delivered to end users for their own ends and you have to sift through all the ads, outrage and general horror of social media to get to the content you want to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not all bad news. In fact there is very good news: RSS never actually went away. Most websites, whether they advertise it or not, still provide an RSS feed and you can use it right now to take control of how content is delivered to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a screenshot of my RSS aggregator this morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/readkit-screenshot-1024x621.png&#34; alt=&#34;My RSS Reader&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I subscribe to nearly two hundred feeds. That sounds overwhelming but while some sites publish multiple times per day, some only put out a handful a year. I can scan through the headlines of all of these sites in a few minutes. It would be very difficult to keep track of that content without RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use RSS to keep track of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter accounts &amp;amp; hashtags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reddit subreddits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newspapers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My feed reader can do clever stuff like filtering out certain key words or phrases. I can, for example, filter out anything related to politics or written by Cory Doctorow. I can organise my feeds into folders - so if I want to avoid the news one day I can just skip that folder, or mark the whole thing read and pretend nothing happened that day. One of the biggest benefits for me is that I’m less likely to open my browser and get lost down the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Internet%20rabbit%20hole&#34;&gt;rabbit hole&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting started:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get started with RSS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up for an account with one of the many feed aggregators. Some of the more popular ones are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feedly.com&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsblur.com&#34;&gt;Newsblur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theoldreader.com&#34;&gt;The Old Reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inoreader.com/&#34;&gt;Inoreader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these have mobile applications - some have desktop companions too. I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/readkit/id588726889&#34;&gt;Readkit&lt;/a&gt; on OSX and &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/lire-rss-reader/id1531976425&#34;&gt;Lire&lt;/a&gt; on iOS. Many people like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reederapp.com/&#34;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt;. There are options for other operating systems, and the web applications don’t care what OS you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to some feeds. Most readers will automatically find the feed if you put in the address of the homepage. If you’re short of inspiration you could take a look at my &lt;a href=&#34;https://hinged.blog/blogroll/&#34;&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at your technical wizardry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
