<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on HINGED</title>
    <link>https://hinged.blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on HINGED</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hinged.blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Breen on Craft Docs</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#robert-breen-craft</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#robert-breen-craft</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://robertbreen.com&#34;&gt;Robert Breen&lt;/a&gt; has written a nice overview of why he&amp;rsquo;s settled on Craft for his note-taking. We both tried Obsidian before arriving at Craft, and seem to have arrived at  the same conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://robertbreen.com/2021/12/15/the-craft-app-a-year-of-magical-linking/&#34;&gt;The Craft App —A Year of Magical Linking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished A Carnival of Snackery, by David Sedaris on 2021-12-14</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#carnival-of-snackery</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#carnival-of-snackery</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/9781408707876.jpg" />&lt;p&gt;In some ways, David Sedaris is very relatable. Well, as relatable as someone who works in a garden shed can be to a multi-millionaire, multi-home owning, best-selling author. He says things out loud that I would only say in my head, but it’s nice to know that someone else has these terrible thoughts, too. Enabling, even, in times where people are scared to offend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this isn’t as enjoyable as the previous diaries. The highlights, as always, are the interactions with his family and his ascerbic observations of the people that he meets. Sadly, he dedicates vast swathes of the book to his talks, plane journeys and hotel stays; which basically makes it a shit travel journal.&lt;/p&gt;
Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished The Best of Me, by David Sedaris on 2021-11-27</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-best-of-me</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-best-of-me</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/the-best-of-me.jpg" />&lt;p&gt;It’s David Sedaris. The best bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve read most of these before, but David Sedaris is someone that is worth re-reading. There are some laugh-out-loud moments, some touching ones, and many where I put my hand to my mouth, thinking: &lt;em&gt;Did he actually just say that?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would be the book to give someone who has never read a Sedaris essay before.&lt;/p&gt;
Rating: 👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Falling, by T.J Newman on 2021-11-16</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#falling</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#falling</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/falling.jpg" />&lt;p&gt;This book was just what I needed. It&amp;rsquo;s cheesy, full of sterotypes and has plot holes that you could fly a jumbo jet through - but it was &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; and just rolled along.&lt;/p&gt;
Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Calypso, by David Sedaris on 2021-11-13</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#calypso</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#calypso</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/calypso.jpeg" />Rating: 👍👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Mexican Gothic, by Silvia Moreno-Garcia on 2021-11-13</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#mexican-gothic</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#mexican-gothic</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/mexican-gothic.jpeg" />Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished The Ashes of London, by Andrew Taylor on 2021-11-07</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#ashesoflondon</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#ashesoflondon</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/ashesoflondon.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The RSS Discovery Engine</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#202110-the-rss-discovery-engine</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 17:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#202110-the-rss-discovery-engine</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding personal websites is increasingly difficult. I usually find new people through blog rolls, or word of mouth. That works, to an extent,  but it feels a bit hit and miss. Enormous websites, with carefully crafted SEO, pollute search engine results and make them almost useless for blogs unless you specifically know who you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good things are happening, though. Several web-rings and directories have popped up in recent years that aid serendipitous discovery, and if you’re a regular consumer of RSS, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rdengine.herokuapp.com&#34;&gt;The RSS Discovery Engine&lt;/a&gt; is a useful tool. Feed it with an RSS feed, and it will crawl through the feed looking for other links that have RSS feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty neat!&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Klara and the Sun, by Kazuo Ishiguro on 2021-10-21</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#klaraandthesun</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#klaraandthesun</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/klaraandthesun.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The 20-page rule</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#202110-the-20-page-rule</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 20:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#202110-the-20-page-rule</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From The Guardian:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2012/aug/03/life-writing-mark-billingham-interview&#34;&gt;Mark Billingham&lt;/a&gt;, the writer of the Tom Thorne crime novels. Speaking at Cheltenham literary festival, he said that if a book hadn’t gripped you after 20 pages, then it was OK not just to give up on it but to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thetimes.co.uk/article/mark-billingham-if-youre-not-gripped-in-the-first-20-pages-dont-read-on-twtkt337m&#34;&gt;“throw it across the room angrily”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with the sentiment, but twenty pages is quick to judge. My rule is 10% or 100 pages, whichever comes first. If I’m not enjoying it by then, I’ll put it down and know that I&amp;rsquo;ve given it a fair crack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is always slight regret, though, like it’s my fault for not &lt;em&gt;getting&lt;/em&gt; it. After all, the book got through a bunch of hurdles to get published and so who am I to say it’s crap? But any regret is outweighed by not having to go through the slog of reading a book that I am not enjoying. Reading is supposed to be fun, not a chore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe throwing it across the room would help..&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished A Psalm for the Wild-Built, by Becky Chambers on 2021-10-12</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#psalmforthewildbuilt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#psalmforthewildbuilt</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/psalmforthewildbuilt.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The perils of productivity systems</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#202110-the-perils-of-productivity-systems</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 15:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#202110-the-perils-of-productivity-systems</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alanralph.co.uk/hooked-on-to-do-lists/&#34;&gt;Alan Ralph&lt;/a&gt; got me thinking about ‘productivity’ apps and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s taken me a long time to realise that I need to treat productivity tools and systems like prescribed medication. They’re fine in limited doses and for specific purposes, but overindulgence is risky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are apps that might make you more efficient, but that’s not the same as being productive. Productivity isn’t born from a system, or an application. It’s a mindset. It’s good habits. It’s discipline. It’s being aligned with your responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I’m being unproductive, it isn’t because my system failed, or that my software needs replacing. It’s because I’m tired, or bored, or unhappy. It’s because I ate that massive Cornish Pasty at lunch and my blood sugar is through the roof. It’s because I’d rather be doing something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to be happy with the tools that you use, and there’s nothing wrong with changing up your systems and processes. But at some point you have to stick with something, because any gains in efficiency are lost in the time spent looking for a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Six months with the Oculus Quest</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#2021-10-05-six-months-with-the-oculus-quest-2</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 19:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#2021-10-05-six-months-with-the-oculus-quest-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve owned my Oculus Quest 2 for around 6 months. Long enough to test its capabilities properly. Here’s my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only previous experience with VR is with the PSVR, which was&amp;hellip; underwhelming. It was heavy, low resolution, had a crazy tethering cable and suffered from the low-power of the decade-old PS4 that was powering it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quest 2 is standalone - no PC required. It’s basically a powerful android device, with a high-quality screen (2k per eye), fresnel lenses and infra-red tracking. And it’s £300 - which is a steal when compared to any other consumer VR product. How good could it be? Surprisingly, very good indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PC gamers gamers won&amp;rsquo;t be impressed by the graphics. Even so, games like The Climb, Beat Saber &amp;amp; SUPERHOT are a lot of fun, and there is enough content in VR  ‘experiences’ to keep non-gamers entertained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also a great way to watch your own media. The Quest will happily play 4k video from my NAS over Wi-Fi. Find a comfy chair, launch &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oculus.com/experiences/quest/2497738113633933/?locale=en_GB&#34;&gt;BigScreenVR&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oculus.com/experiences/quest/2063931653705427/?locale=en_GB&#34;&gt;Skybox&lt;/a&gt; and you’re transported to your own personal movie theatre with a thirty-foot screen and surround sound. You can even watch 3D video on the cinema screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/d13a4f6f-71ac-4e3d-ae1f-d0b1f6efc2cd.jpeg&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Watching In the Shadow of the Moon&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tracking works well, and you can use your hands in good lighting conditions. Everything seems to fall apart in the dark through. My favourite feature is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d73PfTXZDvo&#34;&gt;Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, which invites you to draw out a play area and warns if you stray too close to the edge by fading in a star-trek style holographic wall. It’s very cool and means that I can move freely around my room without worrying about knocking the telly over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have only a couple of criticisms. First, you need a Facebook account to activate the device. Second, and this is more a criticism of the technology itself rather than of the Quest specifically, the sweet spot (the area that is in focus) of the fresnel lenses is tiny. This means that you need to move your head to look around rather than move your eyes. You get used to it, but it can be irritating. Lastly, you’re always going to look like a complete dork when wearing the headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting technology, and now enough to take a punt on.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Domains on iCloud Mail</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#icloud-custom-domains</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#icloud-custom-domains</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the neat things that was quietly announced as part of the iOS 15 rollout is the ability to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-gb/HT212514&#34;&gt;custom domains with iCloud Mail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a long, self-inflicted and complicated history with email. I self-hosted for many years (stupid, don’t do it), then moved to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastmail.com&#34; title=&#34;Fastmail&#34;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt; (too expensive), on to &lt;a href=&#34;https://zoho.eu&#34; title=&#34;Zoho&#34;&gt;Zoho&lt;/a&gt; (too business focussed) and then for the past year, &lt;a href=&#34;https://migadu.com&#34;&gt;Migadu&lt;/a&gt;. Migadu have been great, and I’ve no complaints. It’s a cheap, reliable &amp;amp; no-nonsense service. But moving my domains over to iCloud makes sense because the cost is included in Apple services that I already pay for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process was super-easy, and I was up and running in around fifteen minutes. I’m trialling it with my personal domains for a couple of weeks. If all goes well, I’ll move our communal domain over too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to reduce the amount of stuff that I administer (and pay for), so this has been an unexpected and not unpleasant win.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Dump: September 2021</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#link-dump-202109</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#link-dump-202109</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A random collection of content that I enjoyed in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.404pagefound.com/&#34;&gt;Vintage websites that are still online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CatchWrestling/status/1214317590329331714?s=20&#34;&gt;Do you wanna do my dishes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/julianem33/status/1422196740028084226?s=21&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think about this tweet every single day of my life.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6gzr1INIScI&#34;&gt;Recreating the Walter Mitty Longboard Scene in Iceland! - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/aug/29/readers-reply-when-and-why-did-men-stop-wearing-hats&#34;&gt;When and why did men stop wearing hats?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/oddlyterrifying/comments/padkby/jeff_lee_johnsons_paintings_the_more_you_stare/&#34;&gt;Jeff Lee Johnson&amp;rsquo;s paintings. The more you stare the more you see. : oddlyterrifying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://search.marginalia.nu/&#34;&gt;A search engine that favors text-heavy sites and punishes modern web design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Billy Summers, by Stephen King on 2021-09-21</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#billy-summers</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#billy-summers</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/billy-summers.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Electronic Ink</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/essays/electronic-ink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/essays/electronic-ink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At midnight on July 15th 2005, thousands of people were queueing to get their hands on a hardback copy of Harry Potter &amp;amp; The Half-Blood Prince. I sat at home and waited. Taking advantage of time-zones, a worldwide army of volunteers coordinated a massive transcription effort and released it as an ebook, which I read in my Palm PDA the next morning. That was my first experience of reading fiction electronically, and while imperfect, it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I didn’t know at the time was that a year earlier Sony had released the first commercial electronic book reader in Japan, called the Librie. I ordered one in January 2006 after reading an &lt;a href=&#34;https://boingboing.net/2004/07/02/sonys-librie-ebook-r.html&#34;&gt;article on BoingBoing&lt;/a&gt;. It was my first international purchase, a fact that I remember because I was terrified that it wouldn’t arrive and that I’d be out of pocket by five hundred quid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been a couple of electronic devices in my lifetime that have been so unlike anything released before that they elicit genuine amazement. The iPod touch was one. The Librie was another. It was the first example of an e-ink screen, which was low resolution by today’s standards, but quite remarkable back then. The software was in Japanese, though there was a hack to turn bits of it to English, and it was slow — but I didn’t pick up a paper book the whole time I owned it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/sony-librie.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;My Sony Librie&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;My Sony Librie&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve owned tons of e-ink devices since then. Sony and Amazon ruled the market for a while, but there’s now a plethora of companies doing interesting things with e-ink. Boox, Kobo and Pocketbook make e-readers that leave the Kindle in the dust, and companies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://supernote.com.cn&#34;&gt;Supernote&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://remarkable.com&#34;&gt;Remarkable&lt;/a&gt; are making some compelling note-taking devices with the larger screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about e-ink as a display technology is its limitations. It doesn’t do colour, and the refresh rate is abysmal - so the only thing it’s any good for is displaying single pages of information. It’s the one piece of technology that I own that acts as an antidote to all the other technology I own. There are no ads, and no tracking. No infinite scroll or notifications. It does one thing only: let me escape this world for other worlds, uninterrupted - at least for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a beacon of positivity</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#beacon-of-positivity</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#beacon-of-positivity</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently read through some of my old posts. I’m more of a ‘hit and run’ type of blogger, so it’s not something I do very often, if ever. Many of my posts over the past couple of years are on subjects that generate negative emotions (politics, social media) or are negative in sentiment (general moans &amp;amp; gripes). I’m not thrilled about this, so I’ve unpublished everything prior to this year pending review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;crappy-drawing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/blog-positivity-graph.svg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet has reached heightened levels of toxicity over the past couple of years, and if you are &lt;em&gt;‘very online’&lt;/em&gt; - as many of us are - there is a risk that on-line toxicity &amp;amp; negativity bleeds out into the real world, affecting our well-being, our work, and our relationships. I might play only a tiny part, but it is not my desire to contribute to the global levels of negativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say that I can’t write about negative subjects, or that I should become a beacon of positivity, but that I shouldn’t write about negative things just to get them off my chest. While it makes me feel better, it might have the opposite effect on a reader that is already having a bad day. I’m a big believer in people owning their words. I’m owning mine, and taking some back.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Weights &amp; Measures</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#weights-and-measures</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#weights-and-measures</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two systems of measurement in use in the UK: Imperial and Metric. There is no good reason to use two. That’s just the type of people we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Imperial system uses yards for distance, pounds for weight and gallons for volume. Dividing a ‘yard’ into three gives you a ‘foot’, and one ‘foot’ is divisible by twelve to create an ‘inch’. A mile is 1760 yards (or eight furlongs). A ‘pound’ is divisible by 16 to make an ounce. Going the other way, multiply it by 14 to make a ‘stone’, or by 2000 to make a ‘ton’. A gallon is made up of 8 pints, and pints are divided into fractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sense? No. No, it doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metric, which we all know and love, is a decimal system based on meters for measuring distance, kilograms for weight and litres for volume. It’s easy to remember and calculate. One meter is a hundred centimetres. A thousand meters is a kilometre. One thousand millilitres is a litre. All very sensible, and the UK standardised on this system in the 1960s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no good reason to use anything other than metric, but we intermittently use imperial measurements for weight, height and area. Ask anyone in the UK how much they weigh and you’ll get an answer in stones and pounds. Sales brochures for houses display the floor area in square feet. The entirety of our transport system is in imperial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m replacing our bathroom, and I can tell you that the people that manufacture plumbing supplies also missed the news that we switched to metric forty years ago. If I want some pipe, it comes in meters. But if I want to buy a tap connector, it will be in fractions of inches. Occasionally, they mix the two on one product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is no way to run a country.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Just get the f**cking vaccine</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#just-get-the-fucking-vaccine</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#just-get-the-fucking-vaccine</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wendy Molyneux makes an impassioned and eloquent plea to vaccine sceptics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, if you are reading this essay then congratulations, you are still alive. And if you are alive, then you have either gotten the COVID-19 vaccine, or you still have the opportunity to get the vaccine against COVID-19. And holy fuck, if you aren’t fucking vaccinated against COVID-19, then you need to get fucking vaccinated right now. I mean, what the fuck? Fuck you. Get vaccinated. Fuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many fucks are given in the full essay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/oh-my-fucking-god-get-the-fucking-vaccine-already-you-fucking-fucks&#34;&gt;McSweeny&amp;rsquo;s Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Digital Footprints</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#on-digital-footprints</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#on-digital-footprints</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much energy does your digital self consume, and what can you do to minimise it? Scott Nesbit has been thinking about it this week, and it’s worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of energy used for internet applications is staggering. In 2018, Google estimated that a typical search used as much energy as a 60-watt lightbulb does in 17 seconds&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Imagine that, billions of times over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the overall environmental impact depends on where the energy comes from. Many data centres in Europe are transitioning to renewable energy, as are our homes with the rise of wind and solar. Regardless, it’s something worth thinking about as we wander around our digital universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://buttondown.email/weeklymusings/archive/weekly-musings-125-on-digital-footprints/&#34;&gt;Weekly Musings 125 - On Digital Footprints&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://e360.yale.edu/features/energy-hogs-can-huge-data-centers-be-made-more-efficient&#34;&gt;Yale.edu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Hot Stew, by Fiona Mozley on 2021-08-28</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#hot-stew</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#hot-stew</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/hotstew.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished The Hunting Party, by Lucy Foley on 2021-08-25</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#thehuntingparty</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#thehuntingparty</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/huntingparty.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware the hot take</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#beware-the-hot-take</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#beware-the-hot-take</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ignore the people offering simple solutions to complex problems. There are no simple or right answers, just choices and consequences.&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding a stolen scooter with AirTags</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#man-finds-stolen-scooter-with-airtags</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#man-finds-stolen-scooter-with-airtags</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I lose stuff all the time. AirTags are the hi-tech solution from Apple, but I don’t feel like buying another product to micro-manage my deficiencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, this tweet from Dan Guido offers an interesting insight into their possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;My scooter was stolen last week. Unknown to the thief, I hid two Airtags inside it. I was able to use the Apple Find My network and UWB direction finding to recover the scooter today. Here’s how it all went down:&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dan Guido (@dguido) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dguido/status/1424921645483966466?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;August 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished The Testaments, by Margaret Atwood on 2021-08-09</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-testaments</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-testaments</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/The_Testaments_Atwood_novel.png" />Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stray</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#stray</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#stray</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stray, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://stray.game/&#34;&gt;Blue Twelve Studio&lt;/a&gt;, looks like a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8R-splyERsI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the highly anticipated video game immerses players in a futuristic metropolis as a lonely, injured feline in search of its family. With the help of a drone named B-12, the sprightly creature has to evade the threats of the dystopian city as it roams the neon-lit alleys, leaps through rundown, graffiti-covered buildings, and nuzzles up to human-like robots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thisiscolossal.com/2021/08/stray-video-game/&#34;&gt;Colossal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Link: The most unbelievable things about life before smartphones</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#link-the-most-unbelievable-things-about-life-before-smartphones</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#link-the-most-unbelievable-things-about-life-before-smartphones</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matt Ruby opines at length on the world before smartphones. It is a lovely chunk of nostalgia, and the whole piece will have a specific age group nodding along in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;News was not breaking and I was not alerted. Being elite was a good thing and being a Nazi frowned upon. Scientists were trusted and conspiracy theories were for tinfoil kooks. The only content users generated was letters to the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consumed news once a day by reading a paper that stained my hands. I stumbled upon random articles I would never have selected based on the headline. The ads I saw were untargeted shotgun blasts. Quizzes were just for students and I did not know which ice cream flavor matched my personality, who should play my BFF in a movie of my life, or which Disney prince I should have a threesome with. I rarely got to feel outraged by the words of people I’d never met. For that, I had to rely on family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could use a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; more offline in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mattruby.substack.com/p/the-most-unbelievable-things-about&#34;&gt;The most unbelievable things about life before smartphones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Drowning Doesn’t Look Like Drowning</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#link-drowning-doesnt-look-like-drowning</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#link-drowning-doesnt-look-like-drowning</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article in Slate is an excellent guide to spotting the signs that someone is drowning, which looks nothing like you think it does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I nearly drowned as a child. More than once, actually (I am that dumb). I went too far under with a snorkel, breathed in a lung full of water, and then couldn’t get myself back to the surface. Luckily, a bystander knew the signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://slate.com/technology/2013/06/rescuing-drowning-children-how-to-know-when-someone-is-in-trouble-in-the-water.amp?__twitter_impression=true&#34;&gt;SLATE | Drowning Doesn’t Look Like Drowning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos from September 25th, 2021</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#photos-from-september-25th-2021</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#photos-from-september-25th-2021</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0783-edited-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0777-edited.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0780-edited.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;City of Lincoln, Lincolnshire&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunisa Lee in the New York Times</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#sunisa-lee-in-the-new-york-times</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#sunisa-lee-in-the-new-york-times</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fantastic work from the dev team at the New York Times, showing the extraordinary talent of gymnast Sunisa Lee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee got into gymnastics when she was 6 years old, after watching videos on YouTube. “Once I started, I just couldn’t stop,” she said. “It looked so fun, and I wanted to try it myself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep scrolling up and down and thinking &amp;lsquo;how on earth can someone even do that?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/sports/olympics/suni-lee-gymnastics.html&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Troubled Blood, by Robert Galbraith on 2021-07-27</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#troubled-blood</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#troubled-blood</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/s-l640.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished A Sport and a Pastime, by James Salter on 2021-07-25</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#a-sport-and-a-pastime</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#a-sport-and-a-pastime</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/9780374530501.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Mr Wilder &amp; Me, by Jonathan Coe on 2021-07-25</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#mr-wilder-me</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#mr-wilder-me</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/Jonathan-Coe-600x927-1.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished The Death of Eli Gold, by David Baddiel on 2021-07-25</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-death-of-eli-gold</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-death-of-eli-gold</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/9200000000908811.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2021 iPhone Photography Awards</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#the-2021-ipp-awards</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#the-2021-ipp-awards</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some lovely photos here, and quite a few taken with older models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/Lifestyle-3rd-Valerie-Helbich-Poschacher-1000x750-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;La vue des filles, by Valerie Helbich-Poschacher&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s that saying: &amp;lsquo;the best camera is the one that you have with you&amp;rsquo; - and it&amp;rsquo;s true. I can tell the difference between a shot taken with my iPhone and one taken with my Sony NEX, but the iPhone (or any other phone) is good enough, and it&amp;rsquo;s always with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ippawards.com/2021-winning-photographers/&#34;&gt;https://www.ippawards.com/2021-winning-photographers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tens of thousands</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#tens-of-thousands</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#tens-of-thousands</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are interesting philosophical discussions around whether the costs associated with locking down the economy can be offset by the number who then do not die of COVID-19.  The answer is probably no, but that&amp;rsquo;s a tough sell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the bowels of government, someone (or some people) has determined that a certain number of deaths is the pill that has to be swallowed to allow the economy to open up again. They’ve been pretty cagey about what that number is. Prof Andrew Hayward, the head of the Institute of Epidemiology and Health Care at University College London, says that it is in the &amp;lsquo;low tens of thousands’ - &lt;em&gt;if we are cautious&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last 24 hours, more people tested positive for COVID in the UK than in any other country.&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos from May 30th</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#photos-from-may-31st</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#photos-from-may-31st</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0530-1024x759.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0523-1024x681.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0532-1024x721.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tent Peg</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#link-the-tent-peg</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#link-the-tent-peg</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zac, at The Tent Peg blog, is writing beautiful essays about his various walks around nice bits of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve bookmarked some for later in the year. It feels like such a long time since I’ve walked up a big hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://thetentpeg.co.uk/2021/04/21/hope-x-mam-tor-x-great-ridge/&#34;&gt;The Tent Peg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Terror</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#the-terror</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#the-terror</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terror is now streaming on BBC iPlayer, three whole years after the US release. I watched the first two episodes tonight and it’s every bit as good as I hoped it would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Terror-Dan-Simmons/dp/0593057627/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1618397564&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;novel of the same name&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Simmons which tells a fictionalised account of Sir John Franklin’s expedition to find the North-West Passage. It’s terrifying, but one of my favourite books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/869EDE2D-1211-4F58-9F6B-B542823E7EE1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;HMS Erebus in the Ice - Francois Musin. 1846.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HMS Erebus in the Ice - Francois Musin. 1846.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real story of the expedition is a good tale on its own. Michael Palin has done as good of a job as anyone in putting it down on paper in ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Erebus-Story-Ship-Michael-Palin/dp/184794812X&#34;&gt;Erebus&lt;/a&gt;’, which is well worth a read too.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blooming Lovely</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#blooming-lovely</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#blooming-lovely</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/9fad3c0ca8a4ae3828a45a6eccfeafe5-1024x768.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Cherry Blossom at Pately Bridge, Harrogate&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Player of Games, by Iain M. Banks on 2021-04-12</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#player-of-games</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#player-of-games</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/iu-1.jpeg" />Rating: 👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Later, by Stephen King on 2021-04-07</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#later</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#later</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/1789096499.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dystopian Quote of the Day</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#dystopian-quote-of-the-day</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#dystopian-quote-of-the-day</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The truth is machines have not taken over, but they are here to stay. We need to make our peace with them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nick Clegg. Head of Global Affairs and Communications at Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christ, Nick. That’s a bit much.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Girls, by Nic Kelman on 2021-03-31</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#girls</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#girls</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/DBB20BB5-775E-42D8-B4D2-CA5E7C90E420.jpeg" />Rating: 👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixed at the time of writing</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#faith</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#faith</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I find the decline of organised religion interesting as a sociological phenomenon. What happens when the structure and philosophy underpinning our legal and moral frameworks falls away?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Church membership in the USA has dipped below 50% for the first time(1). That&amp;rsquo;s a big deal, because the USA is one of the most devoutly Christian countries in the West, and its religious leaders wield a great deal of political influence. The figures reflect what has been happening in the UK for decades—an accelerating decline of membership and attendance across all demographics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of people in the UK self-identifying as Christian stood at 58% in 2011, dropping 12% since 2001(3). The average Church of England service now fills less than thirty seats(2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one can agree on why, but I think the following quote is as good an answer as any:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not about churches not being able to answer questions clearly; the reality is just that fewer people believe in gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26621572&#34;&gt;Freak_NL / Hacker News_&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.gallup.com/poll/341963/church-membership-falls-below-majority-first-time.aspx&#34;&gt;Gallup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psephizo.com/life-ministry/what-is-happening-to-church-of-england-attendance/&#34;&gt;What is happening to CoE attandance?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ReligionintheUnitedKingdom#Statistics&#34;&gt;Wikipedia - Religion in the UK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt McConaughey talks to Tim Ferris</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#matt-mcconaughey-talks-to-tim-ferris</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#matt-mcconaughey-talks-to-tim-ferris</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matt McConaughey recorded a wide-ranging interview with Tim Ferris back in October last year. It’s a great listen and confirmed his place on my list of people I would like to have over for dinner. I’d never heard of him until True Detective, then I saw him later the same year in Interstellar and he instantly became one of my favourite actors. He’s an interesting bloke too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In it, Matt speaks of the importance of introspection as a tool for personal change. He’s kept a journal for over thirty years, and explains how he uses it to help him navigate through life. I’m good at introspection, but I’m not good at acting on it. I’ve kept a journal since 2005. Sometimes I will go weeks without writing in it — but I’m still glad to have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also speaks about the need for society to have shared values, and of politics and politicians not being good delivery vehicles for that sort of thing. I’ve thought about this a lot. Our shared values, traditionally, came from religion — but as religion fades, where do we get those shared values? We’re grappling with this now, but it will become more important in the decades ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a fun listen, and worth your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/474-matthew-mcconaughey-power-no-thank-you-key-life/id863897795?i=1000495276979&#34;&gt;The Tim Ferris Show #474&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Good Ship Wingardium Leviosa</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#the-good-ship-wingardium-leviosa</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#the-good-ship-wingardium-leviosa</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/117387798_apex_hovering_ship_illusion_03.jpg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a complicated ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-cornwall-56286719&#34;&gt;scientific explanation&lt;/a&gt;’ to explain how this ship appears to be floating in the air, but a more logical one would be that those pesky kids from Hogwarts are running riot again.&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentines Day</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#valentines-day</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#valentines-day</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The origins of Valentines day as a celebration are thought to have begun with the Roman festival of Lupercalia, where, to celebrate the mythological founders of Rome, the Romans would do very odd things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The festival involved the sacrifice of a goat and a dog; the goat’s hide would be cut into strips and dipped in its blood, and priests, called Luperci, would then carry these strips and gently slap crop fields and women with them, with the latter being eager for this treatment as they believed that it would make them more fertile in the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ancient.eu/Valentine&#39;s_Day/&#34;&gt;Ancient.EU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sounds more fun than trudging around looking for greetings cards.&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Consider Phlebas, by Iain M. Banks on 2021-03-03</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#consider-phlebas</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#consider-phlebas</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/51uT5CeSI3L._SX316_BO1204203200_.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Perseverance</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#perseverance</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#perseverance</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re getting pretty good at lobbing robots across the cosmos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new photos from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Perseverance rover are incredible. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what it discovers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/Eum9z6TVEAAjZOT-1024x768.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking out from the Hazard Camera - NASA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/EvbiuObVgAMs5fQ-1024x763.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view from Jezero Crater - NASA&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Not a plant influencer</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#not-a-plant-influencer</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#not-a-plant-influencer</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zanib Hussain Alvi writes of her love of blogs as a part of her &lt;a href=&#34;https://whyisthisinteresting.substack.com/p/the-monday-media-diet-with-zanab&#34;&gt;media diet&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last best thing I read was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://daughterofthesoil.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; of some random British woman at the edge of the Cotswolds, writing about cross breeding heritage varieties of peas like Gregor fucking Mendel and how to save seeds to cross breed your own plants. Her last post was two years ago. There’s something about the longer format and distribution or, rather, lack of distribution that makes blogs so special. It was interesting to me because it was interesting to her. I didn’t have to like, subscribe, or make an ongoing commitment to continue to read her blog. She wasn’t selling anything. It felt so refreshing and wholesome to consume information that no one was really trying to actively monetize. She wasn’t trying to be a “plant influencer” but it did reshape what I thought was accessible to me. I have no idea if she’s conventionally attractive, nor do I care. The contrast makes all these apps and their onslaught of notifications seem so absolutely desperate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can also get behind her views on podcasts. Why are they all two hours long? Who has the time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podcasts have absolutely no respect for my time. Most of them could be five minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow Days</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#snow-days</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#snow-days</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0241-1024x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed like everywhere in the country was to get snow except us, but it finally started to fall a couple of days ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s going to stick around long, but we’ll enjoy it while it’s here.&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rating Stuff</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#rating-stuff</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#rating-stuff</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jamie Todd Rubin laments at length on the variety and complexity of rating systems &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jamierubin.net/2021/02/05/5-star-rating-systems/&#34;&gt;on his blog today&lt;/a&gt;. Here is his suggested rating scale:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1-star: Distraught. Way below my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2-stars: Disappointed. I’d expected more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3-stars: Satisfied. Met my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4-stars: Delighted. Exceeded my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-stars: Blown away. Far exceeded my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it might be slightly in jest, but this is precisely the sort of triviality I can get behind.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>The Everything Store</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/essays/the-everything-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/essays/the-everything-store/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I find people like Jeff Bezos fascinating, and not just because they are fabulously wealthy and have more boats than me (for the record, I have none). I would be a rubbish CEO. I can barely drag myself out of bed in the morning. I have the drive and ambition of a lumbering tortoise. How do you build and manage a company of the size and complexity of Amazon? How do you grow it from selling a few books on the internet to what it is now? Think of how many moving parts there are in a company of this size. It’s mind boggling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine going back in time and trying to explain Amazon to someone in the pre-internet days. A store with no shops, that you browse with a computer (let’s not bamboozle them with smartphones just yet), that sells basically &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; and will deliver it to your house in under twenty-four hours. Younger me would think that older me is suffering from a degenerative brain condition.Amazon gets a lot of stick, and so does Jeff Bezos. Amazon has changed how we shop, to the detriment of our high streets, local stores and small businesses. It is a sprawling empire with a market capitalisation larger than the GDP of most countries, employing over a million people. It has its own fleet of aeroplanes and a logistics operation that will soon be bigger than Fedex and UPS. It runs the servers that power most of the internet and will be at the forefront of our experiments with AI in the future. Meanwhile, Jeff Bezos became one of the richest people on the planet, and &lt;em&gt;nobody&lt;/em&gt; likes rich people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it good that a single company holds so much power? On balance, probably.. not? The regulators will have their say on that. I’d say it’s fairly likely that US regulators will force them to spin off their cloud computing platform, AWS. And Amazon’s aversion to paying its fair share of tax will eventually be reconciled. Even so, it’s hard to see anything slowing it down significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would have always been an Amazon of some sort. It’s a natural result of globalisation, capitalism and the internet. Bezos had an idea, implemented it before anyone else - did it better than anyone else - and relentlessly drove it forward into the biggest retail operation on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you think of the company, or the person, it’s one hell of an achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an addendum, it’s often said that money doesn’t make you happy. I think this is bullshit. I would be deliriously happy with a couple of billion in the bank. But putting that to one side for a moment, let me be trivial and remark upon the physical transformation of Jeff Bezos. You’d probably win a fight with Jeff Bezos in 1998, but 2017 Jeff Bezos could rappel out of a helicopter, chase you for ten miles and &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; kick your ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/DE0j0DbU0AAc4Q1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing in the Dark</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#dancing-in-the-dark</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#dancing-in-the-dark</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bruce knows how to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x7lfzARGXGw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I get up in the evenin&#39;&lt;br&gt;
And I ain&amp;rsquo;t got nothin&#39; to say&lt;br&gt;
I come home in the mornin&#39;&lt;br&gt;
I go to bed feelin&#39; the same way&lt;br&gt;
I ain&amp;rsquo;t nothin&#39; but tired&lt;br&gt;
Man, I&amp;rsquo;m just tired and bored with myself&lt;br&gt;
Hey there, baby, I could use just a little help&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t start a fire&lt;br&gt;
You can&amp;rsquo;t start a fire without a spark&lt;br&gt;
This gun&amp;rsquo;s for hire&lt;br&gt;
Even if we&amp;rsquo;re just dancin&#39; in the dark&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Messages keeps gettin&#39; clearer&lt;br&gt;
Radio&amp;rsquo;s on and I&amp;rsquo;m movin&#39; &amp;lsquo;round my place&lt;br&gt;
I check my look in the mirror&lt;br&gt;
Wanna change my clothes, my hair, my face&lt;br&gt;
Man, I ain&amp;rsquo;t gettin&amp;rsquo; nowhere&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m just livin&#39; in a dump like this&lt;br&gt;
There&amp;rsquo;s somethin&#39; happenin&#39; somewhere&lt;br&gt;
Baby, I just know that there is&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t start a fire&lt;br&gt;
You can&amp;rsquo;t start a fire without a spark&lt;br&gt;
This gun&amp;rsquo;s for hire&lt;br&gt;
Even if we&amp;rsquo;re just dancin&#39; in the dark&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You sit around gettin&#39; older&lt;br&gt;
There&amp;rsquo;s a joke here somewhere and it&amp;rsquo;s on me&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll shake this world off my shoulders&lt;br&gt;
Come on, baby, this laugh&amp;rsquo;s on me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stay on the streets of this town&lt;br&gt;
And they&amp;rsquo;ll be carvin&#39; you up alright&lt;br&gt;
They say you gotta stay hungry&lt;br&gt;
Hey baby, I&amp;rsquo;m just about starvin&#39; tonight&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m dyin&#39; for some action&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m sick of sittin&#39; &amp;lsquo;round here tryin&amp;rsquo; to write this book&lt;br&gt;
I need a love reaction&lt;br&gt;
Come on now, baby, gimme just one look&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t start a fire&lt;br&gt;
Sittin&#39; &amp;lsquo;round cryin&amp;rsquo; over a broken heart&lt;br&gt;
This gun&amp;rsquo;s for hire&lt;br&gt;
Even if we&amp;rsquo;re just dancin&#39; in the dark&lt;br&gt;
You can&amp;rsquo;t start a fire&lt;br&gt;
Worryin&#39; about your little world fallin&#39; apart&lt;br&gt;
This gun&amp;rsquo;s for hire&lt;br&gt;
Even if we&amp;rsquo;re just dancin&#39; in the dark&lt;br&gt;
Even if we&amp;rsquo;re just dancin&#39; in the dark&lt;br&gt;
Even if we&amp;rsquo;re just dancin&#39; in the dark&lt;br&gt;
Even if we&amp;rsquo;re just dancin&#39; in the dark&lt;br&gt;
Hey baby&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Coldheart Canyon, by Clive Barker on 2021-02-01</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#coldheart-canyon</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#coldheart-canyon</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/coldheart-uk3-500.jpg" />Rating: 👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers, please</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#papers-please</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#papers-please</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Racial abuse: Is ending anonymity on social media the answer? &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/pkM7j00dQh&#34;&gt;https://t.co/pkM7j00dQh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rory Cellan-Jones (@ruskin147) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruskin147/status/1356302526715457536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For public forums, the evidence shows that anonyminity isn&amp;rsquo;t conducive to good community. Twitter is a toxic mess, mostly because people can hide behind fake names and profile pictures and spunk out whatever is on their mind without consequence.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished The Invisible Life of Addie LaRue, by V.E. Schwab on 2021-01-31</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-invisible-life-of-addie-larue</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-invisible-life-of-addie-larue</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/51FVPBt51ZL._SX329_BO1204203200_.jpg" />&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March is such a fickle month. It is the seam between winter and spring—though. [Loc: 160]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She pauses at MEMOIR, studying the titles on the spines, so many I’s and Me’s and My’s, possessive words for possessive lives. What a luxury, to tell one’s story. To be read, remembered. [Loc: 1398]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He runs his hand through Robbie’s hair. Dry, it is the color of burnt sugar, a tawny shade somewhere between brown and red, depending on the light. [Loc: 1554]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember seeing that picture and realizing that photographs weren’t real. There’s no context, just the illusion that you’re showing a snapshot of a life, but life isn’t snapshots, it’s fluid. So photos are like fictions. [Loc: 4188]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has seen maps of course, but ink and paper hold nothing to this. To the salt smell, the murmur of waves, the hypnotic draw of the tide. To the scope and scale of the sea, and the knowledge that somewhere, beyond the horizon, there is more. [Loc: 5408]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addie was raised to kneel in the little stone chapel in the center of Villon, spent days folded into Paris pews. She has listened to the bells, and the organ, and the calls to prayer. And yet, despite it all, she has never understood the appeal. How does a ceiling bring you closer to heaven? If God is so large, why build walls to hold Him in? [Loc: 5462]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I hate war,” he says darkly. “I would have thought you fond of conflict.” “The aftermath breeds art,” he says. “But war makes believers out of cynics. Sycophants desperate for salvation, everyone suddenly clinging to their souls, clutching them close like a matron with her finest pearls.” [Loc: 6480]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That kiss, like a piece of long-awaited punctuation. Not the em dash of an interrupted line, or the ellipsis of a quiet escape, but a period, a closed parenthesis, an end. [Loc: 7766]&lt;/p&gt;
Rating: 👍👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GME day 3</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#gme-day-3</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#gme-day-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matt Levine continues to write very good copy on the unfathomable things that happen when a bunch of Redditors get involved in the stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, he lays out some scenarios of how this is likely to play out (one, albeit unlikely, being the collapse of capitalism), but it sounds like it’s not easy to predict, even for those that do this stuff for a living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is just the case, just inevitably the case, that if you are going to have financial markets that are optimized for those purposes—that are liquid and complete, that attract smart people, that are open to everyone—they are also going to have a certain amount of nonsense. It’s not like WallStreetBets invented financial nonsense! Financial-market nonsense is, like, 70% of what we talk about around here on a normal day. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-05-18/sinful-derivatives-have-their-uses&#34;&gt;How&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-05-23/maybe-companies-will-get-rid-of-cds&#34;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-06-25/regulators-don-t-enjoy-cds-games&#34;&gt;times&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-01-15/sometimes-cds-is-on-the-wrong-company&#34;&gt;have&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-12-13/credit-default-swaps-get-weird-after-sears-bankruptcy&#34;&gt;I&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-03-05/neiman-marcus-does-some-cds-stuff-too&#34;&gt;have written&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-05-01/another-weird-deal-upsets-cds-traders&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloombergquint.com/view/blackstone-may-do-its-cleverest-cds-trade-again&#34;&gt;hedge&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2018-06-28/credit-derivatives-bring-people-together&#34;&gt;funds&lt;/a&gt; tricking each other using credit default swaps? Financial markets exist to foster price discovery and capital formation, but the way they do that is mostly by letting smart people mess with each other all day. WallStreetBets is a new class of smart people messing, quite effectively, with the old ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Levine / Bloomberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know nothing about the stock market, and I&amp;rsquo;m not making any judgement on whether all this is good or bad, but it is absolutely fascinating and at least a tiny bit funny.&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>That is a thing that you can do</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#that-is-a-thing-that-you-can-do</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#that-is-a-thing-that-you-can-do</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2021-01-26/will-wallstreetbets-face-sec-scrutiny-after-gamestop-rally&#34;&gt;Matt Levine&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Money Stuff&amp;rdquo; newsletter&lt;/a&gt;, on what happened when /r/wallstreetbets directed their collective might on Gamestop, precipitating &lt;em&gt;$17 billion dollars&lt;/em&gt; of stock trades and inflating the stock by 180%:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here (via &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.mail.bloombergbusiness.com/click/22761987.263578/aHR0cHM6Ly90d2l0dGVyLmNvbS9Sb2JpbldpZ2cvc3RhdHVzLzEzNTM3ODM0ODE2NDY2NTc1Mzg/600ff07e6413780742239610B7447144c&#34;&gt;Robin Wigglesworth&lt;/a&gt;) is &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.mail.bloombergbusiness.com/click/22761987.263578/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cucmVkZGl0LmNvbS9yL3dhbGxzdHJlZXRiZXRzL2NvbW1lbnRzL2w0c2czdS9jYW5faV9nZXRfYV9mbGFpcl9mb3JfYnV5aW5nX2dtZV9hdF90aGVfbGl0ZXJhbC9na3FmZ3NwLw/600ff07e6413780742239610Bcc9ac1b3&#34;&gt;a post&lt;/a&gt; on Reddit’s r/wallstreetbets forum asking “Can I get a flair for buying GME at the literal top ($155.29)?” (It was not the literal top, but close.) “This is the way,” a chorus of redditors replied. It is &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; way! Gleefully getting top-ticked on a stock—buying it at its highest price ever and then bragging about it as the price collapses—in order to earn the strange respect of your friends on Reddit: That is a thing you can do. You might enjoy it. I am not going to say it is irrational; people have spent their money on worse things. But it is not the sort of rationality that the stock market is set up for. “When stock prices get too high, sensible value motives will take over”: Nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stock exchange is weird. People on the internet are weirder.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tucows</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#remember-tucows</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#remember-tucows</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Internet users of a certain age might remember Tucows as the place that you would go to download pretty much anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out that they are still about, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tucows.com/retired/&#34;&gt;and doing well&lt;/a&gt;. They have just retired the download site after 25 years of operation – but they also own Hover, Enom &amp;amp; Ting; and are the second largest domain registrar in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s cool that they&amp;rsquo;ve weathered the storms and stuck around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/Screenshot-2021-01-21-at-21.51.40.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tucows in 2002&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting, for the fun of it</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#collecting-for-the-fun-of-it</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#collecting-for-the-fun-of-it</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Britain is a nation of collectors. From stamps to coins and military regalia — most folk know someone who collects &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. I had a collection of StarTrek collectibles that I was quite pleased with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It surprised me to learn that there are people that collect bricks. Not gold bricks, &lt;em&gt;building&lt;/em&gt; bricks - the kind houses are built with. Bricks are worthless. Their ultimate destiny is to be ground to rubble and used as hardcore. So, why collect them? I enjoyed organising my Star Trek cards, and these guys - I assume that are guys - enjoy bricks. Happiness makes the world go round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/DraggedImage.png&#34; alt=&#34;Jason Harris’s haul of bricks. (Jason Harris, T-Space architects)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/brick-collecting&#34;&gt;Atlas Obscura: Brick Collecting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Dishonesty is the Second-Best Policy, by David Mitchell on 2021-01-13</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#dishonesty-is-the-second-best-policy</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#dishonesty-is-the-second-best-policy</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/48649871._SY475_.jpg" />&lt;p&gt;The book is a collection of his newspaper columns, and so comes across as dated in places, but his cynical observations on the perversity of modern life are, for me, always worth a read. You either like David Mitchell, or you don&amp;rsquo;t, and will probably fall firmly into one of those camps. Guardian reading lefties will love it. Probably.&lt;/p&gt;
Rating: 👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#experiments</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#experiments</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success, whether massive or modest, shouldn’t be the goal of any experiment that you undertake. The goal can, and perhaps always should, be to learn something new. And, by extension, to learn something about yourself at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://buttondown.email/weeklymusings/archive/weekly-musings-097-on-experimenting/&#34;&gt;Scott Nesbit&lt;/a&gt; / Weekly Musings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experiments don’t have to be grand in scope and scale. It’s obvious, really, but easy to forget.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Dreyer&#39;s English, by Benjamin Dreyer on 2021-01-11</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#dreyers-english</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#dreyers-english</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/dreyersenglish.jpg" />&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of books on the writing process, but this is a fun read and one that I&amp;rsquo;ll keep dipping back into.&lt;/p&gt;
Rating: 👍👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The blogging revolution will be delivered to your inbox</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#the-blogging-revolution-will-be-delivered-to-your-inbox</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#the-blogging-revolution-will-be-delivered-to-your-inbox</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I knew that if I kept blogging for long enough that it would become fashionable again, and it is, sort of, but not in the way that I imagined. While more people are blogging from their own domain — which is fabulous — an enormous number of people are choosing newsletter platforms like Substack and Buttondown instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging isn’t easy. Ask for advice on the internet and you’ll end up with something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innocent: &lt;em&gt;“Oh, hi. I&amp;rsquo;d like to start a blog. Can you help?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nerd: &lt;em&gt;“No problem. That’s easy! Just connect your GitHub account to Netlify and run a custom build pipeline from Hugo and some markdown files”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging is a technical and creative endeavour, requiring a whole host of different skills, a large amount of time, and for most people no recompense other than the joy of doing it. It&amp;rsquo;s not for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsletter startups have solved the problems of difficulty and monetisation, so if people find that newsletters are the best way to distribute their content, and get paid for it (if they want to), then more power to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New to the world of newsletters? Here&amp;rsquo;s a few of my favourites to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://helenlewis.substack.com/p/the-bluestocking-vol-169&#34;&gt;The Bluestocking&lt;/a&gt;, by Helen Lewis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.garbageday.email/&#34;&gt;Garbage Day&lt;/a&gt;, by Ryan Broderick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://heathercoxrichardson.substack.com&#34;&gt;Letters from an American&lt;/a&gt;, by Heather Cox Richardson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soverybeautiful.org/&#34;&gt;Life is so Beautiful&lt;/a&gt;, by Hugh Hollowell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/account/newsletters/money-stuff?source=NLshare&#34;&gt;Money Stuff&lt;/a&gt;, by Matt Levine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS aficionados will be pleased to know that both Buttondown and Substack provide RSS feeds by default, though my preference is to subscribe via my &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.newsblur.com/post/146752875548/newsletters-in-your-newsblur&#34;&gt;NewsBlur email address&lt;/a&gt; so that authors know they&amp;rsquo;ve got a reader.&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nearly 40</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#nearly-40</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#nearly-40</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll be forty in a few months. When I was young, I couldn’t imagine what being forty years old would be like. It seems like such a large and distant number. But it feels smaller now that it approaches, and I’m not particularly fussed about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago, someone asked an open question Hacker News - &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24527978&#34;&gt;What is it like to be old?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; among the hundreds of responses was this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Once you hit 40 you start feeling random pains in places. Sometimes pretty intense pain. Your doctor will have no idea what caused it and tell you it&amp;rsquo;s normal, but let them know if it happens again. And after a while you&amp;rsquo;ll just stop telling them, because it&amp;rsquo;s just a thing that happens now&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Well, at least I haven’t got that to deal with,&lt;/em&gt; I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, I woke up unable to raise my arm above chest level. My elbow is red, hot &amp;amp; swollen with fluid. I didn’t bang or stress it—it just decided that it would not play its usual role for me today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I guess this is how it is now.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished Axioms End, by Lindsay Ellis on 2021-01-06</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#axioms-end</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#axioms-end</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/514wPzi8b8L.jpg" />&lt;p&gt;I’m a sucker for a good first contact story, but found this one underwhelming. The premise was good, but I didn’t gel with the protagonist at all. The author is not frugal with her words, and some of the descriptive passages had me looking for the telephone number of her editor. It’s listed as the first book in a series, but I can’t see me buying any of the others. It has a good rating on Amazon, though, so your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;
Rating: 👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>USA WTF</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#usa-wtf</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#usa-wtf</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Has America always been a bit strange, or is it a new thing? To me it feels like a new thing, but I’m starting to wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Let me tell you why I WILL carry my Glock to Congress. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Government does NOT get to tell me or my constituents how we are allowed to keep our families safe.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I promise to always stand strong for our 2nd Amendment rights.&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/E75tYpdN4B&#34;&gt;https://t.co/E75tYpdN4B&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/qg7QGenrNo&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/qg7QGenrNo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Lauren Boebert (@laurenboebert) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurenboebert/status/1345891049584132097?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2020</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/stream/#2020</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/stream/#2020</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Sunday, one of the large panes of glass in our french doors exploded. There was no external impact. It just gave up on life. That, I thought, just finishes the year perfectly. A final &lt;em&gt;fuck you&lt;/em&gt; from 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many words have been written and will be written, about what a crap year 2020 has been. For me, putting aside externalities, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been as bad as it could have been. I&amp;rsquo;ve missed the get-togethers, cinema, museums and country houses. But there was also much to be glad about: our eldest daughter moving away to university, getting a job and revealing that she can function as a human without our input or opinions; switching jobs and recovering some sanity, building a space of my own, driving less and walking more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus changed our lives in ways that were unimaginable twelve months ago. New behaviours are so entrenched that our youngest daughter remarked on how strange it is that none of the characters on Animal Crossing practice social distancing, or wear a mask. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; normal being replaced by the &lt;em&gt;old&lt;/em&gt; normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m hugely grateful to the bloggers that plug away at their sites week in, week out. I’m grateful for the brief glimpses into your lives and the knowledge that while we&amp;rsquo;re all going through same thing, we deal with it in our own ways. I&amp;rsquo;ve made an effort to reach out and tell you that. I&amp;rsquo;ll continue doing the same in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no willpower and fragile self-esteem, so there are no goals or resolutions for next year. What will be, will be, and it will be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the best.&lt;/p&gt;<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished The New Wilderness, by Diane Cooke on 2020-12-16</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-new-wilderness</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-new-wilderness</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/the-new-wilderness-9781786078223_xlg.jpg" />&lt;p&gt;A group of people are given the opportunity to live in a pristine wilderness. They must survive while leaving no trace on their surroundings. This is a fantastic book, and beautifully written. At two points it literally moved me to tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The salt was the thing that lasted the longest. And after it was gone they discovered that real food tastes like dirt, water, and exertion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Rating: 👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Finished The Glass Hotel, by Emily St. John Mandel on 2020-12-15</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-glass-hotel</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/bookshelf/#the-glass-hotel</guid>
      <description><img src="https://hinged.blog/images/books/glass-hotel.jpg" />&lt;p&gt;There is a lot going on in this book. A ponzi scheme (that bares a remarkable semblance to the Bernie Madoff scheme), a musically talented addict, a trophy wife adjusting to changed circumstances and a beautiful hotel in the remote Canadian wilderness - but somehow, almost unbelievably, it stays coherent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But they were citizens of a shadow country that in his previous life he’d only dimly perceived, a country located at the edge of an abyss. He’d been aware of the shadowland forever, of course. He’d seen its more obvious outposts: shelters fashioned from cardboard under overpasses, tents glimpsed in the bushes alongside expressways, houses with boarded-up doors but a light shining in an upstairs window. He’d always been vaguely aware of its citizens, people who’d slipped beneath the surface of society, into a territory without comfort or room for error. [Loc: 3581]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Rating: 👍👍👍👍<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>Converting my shed to an office</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/essays/converting-my-shed-to-an-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/essays/converting-my-shed-to-an-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The justification for this tale of folly is that my wife and I are home-working, me permanently and my wife for the next couple of months at least. We don&amp;rsquo;t have enough room in the house for a dedicated space. The closest we have is the conservatory, but for at least half the day it bakes you alive. What we do have is a shed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our shed is the standard sized timber-framed thing that you’ll find at the bottom of most British gardens. It’s about ten years old, but has been looked after. I reckoned that I could turn it into a useable office space without much fuss. An article in The Times says that these conversions are known as a &amp;lsquo;shoffice&amp;rsquo; - an amalgamation of shed &amp;amp; office. I am never going to call it that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone famous once said that the best place to start is the beginning. I trundled down to see what my starting point was, then lay down on the floor, curled myself into the fetal position and sobbed quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0560-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Messy shed&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any good shed, it&amp;rsquo;s rammed with junk - but a casual survey suggests that the structure is basically sound. The main faults are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a minor leak on the roof&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a small hole where a mouse has broken in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some water penetration on the walls where the shiplap has deterioriated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can fix that. The game is on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-preparation&#34;&gt;Step 1: Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured that I have enough knowledge about the fundamentals of building construction to take on a project like this - because I live in a house, and how hard can it be? But I would need some sort of plan, if only to reassure other people that I knew what I was doing. The first step was to commission some detailed technical drawings of the structure and dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/shed-planning.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that done, I needed to clear all the junk out. This was a real pain. I decided to dump it in a big pile in the garden. Meanwhile, a significant amount of building materials are piling up in our hallway, increasing the risk that I might have to live in the shed rather than work in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-fix-the-roof&#34;&gt;Step 1: Fix the roof&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old felt on the roof was brittle and porous. I replaced it with some brand-spanking-new long-life roofing felt. It would have been easier if I had bought the right amount of felt, saving me an additional trip to Wickes in the middle of a global pandemic, but the actual work was straight-forward, and I am at least 90% confident that it is water-tight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost of materials: Approximately £60&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-add-some-windows&#34;&gt;Step 2: Add some windows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My shed didn&amp;rsquo;t have any windows. Sitting in the dark didn&amp;rsquo;t sound much fun, so I ordered two panes of UPVC glazing from a local glass factory. At this point I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how I was going to install the glass - so I put that little worry aside for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day came and I started worrying about how I was going to install the glass. The basic plan I came up with was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a timber frame on the inside to support the weight of the glass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut out two holes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make external and internal framing to hold the glass in place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting the holes in the shed was terrifying, because from that point on it’s no longer a good shed - it’s just a shit building with holes in it. Anyway, after much swearing, cutting and hammering I ended up with two framed holes that looked approximately like windows. In my humble but expert opinion, a good window has two desirable features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can see out of it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn’t let the outside weather inside&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give myself full marks for the first one. The second one is more difficult. There is a technical term we use at work - &amp;lsquo;silicone-the-shit-out-of-it&amp;rsquo; - which translates roughly to fixing something by applying lots and lots of silicone sealant. I installed the glass, framed it, applied lots of silicone and crossed my fingers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0571-1-1024x516.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Building the exterior frames&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to replace the rotten sections of cladding with bits removed for the windows - a stroke of good luck rather than good planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost for glass: £28&lt;br&gt;
Cost for other materials: £20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-insulation-and-boarding&#34;&gt;Step 3: Insulation and Boarding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sheds tend to be a bit cold in the winter, so I insulated the walls and ceiling with 20mm polystyrene sheets and then added a layer of thick polythene to keep moisture out. Polystyrene is awful to work with, but cheap and easy for a weakling like me to carry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted finished walls, so plasterboard is realistically the only option for the inside. I can’t skim so the plan is to board it, fill the gaps, slap some paint on and hope for the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/shed-insulation.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step was time-consuming. Because of the small space, each piece of insulation and plasterboard has to be individually cut to size. I asked a friend help me with the boarding - but he’s the annoying sort that insists that I will only learn if I do things myself, so I didn’t save as much time as much as I had hoped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the boards now installed, I filled the gaps with filler, left it to dry and sanded the joints down to create what I hoped (but wasn&amp;rsquo;t) a smooth finish. I also moved the small consumer unit to a better location and reinstalled the light. It&amp;rsquo;s now beginning to look less like a shed and more like a room. I feel like Tim Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0573-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0574-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost: approx £210 (less approx £100 of donated materials)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-4-finishing-off&#34;&gt;Step 4: Finishing off&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am relatively happy with myself again by the time I&amp;rsquo;ve finished painting, and the paint has taken to the plasterboard better than I expected. I built a desk and some storage out of CLS timber &amp;amp; plywood, laid down some laminate, installed some skirting, two double sockets, some blinds and called it a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how it looked on the last day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0616.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a minor technical hitch when I realised that my WiFi doesn’t reach the end of the garden. Well, it does and it doesn’t. Download speeds were great, but upload non-existent. That wouldn’t have bothered me a year ago, but you need a decent amount of upload bandwidth for video calls. I tried Powerline adaptors. They worked, but only at 6mbps (probably because of the distance and the number of circuits). I wasn’t having that when I’ve got a 200mbps connection in the house, so I ran an ethernet cable in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/img_0619-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve had some bad weather over the past week, and no leaks. I&amp;rsquo;m calling it watertight and declaring mission accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
       <item>
      <title>RSS makes the web tolerable again</title>
      <link>https://hinged.blog/essays/rss-makes-the-web-tolerable-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hinged.blog/essays/rss-makes-the-web-tolerable-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in the halcyon days of the early web the large internet portals, like Netscape, Yahoo and AOL, were starting to think about how their customers would access the ever-growing amount of content being produced on the internet. The answer they came up with was ‘syndication’. From the user perspective this was as simple as adding a BBC News or Wired widget on your homepage. If you are as old as me you might even remember doing it. Behind the scenes these content transactions were powered by a syndication protocol called RSS (which stands for ‘Really Simple Syndication’ or ‘Rich Site Summary’, depending on who you ask). Theoretically this was good for everyone: content providers were able to to reach people they would never have reached before, users had control over how and where they receive content, and the portals kept customers on their sites for longer by offering personalised experiences, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/mynetscape.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while RSS was ubiquitous, but it faltered when the larger social networks became the main vehicle of syndicated content - and it didn’t help that it has never been particularly user-friendly. Most people now get their news from social media but recent years have shown that this can be problematic: social media platforms are not neutral content providers. They manipulate how, when and what content is delivered to end users for their own ends and you have to sift through all the ads, outrage and general horror of social media to get to the content you want to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not all bad news. In fact there is very good news: RSS never actually went away. Most websites, whether they advertise it or not, still provide an RSS feed and you can use it right now to take control of how content is delivered to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a screenshot of my RSS aggregator this morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hinged.blog/images/readkit-screenshot-1024x621.png&#34; alt=&#34;My RSS Reader&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I subscribe to nearly two hundred feeds. That sounds overwhelming but while some sites publish multiple times per day, some only put out a handful a year. I can scan through the headlines of all of these sites in a few minutes. It would be very difficult to keep track of that content without RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use RSS to keep track of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter accounts &amp;amp; hashtags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reddit subreddits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newspapers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My feed reader can do clever stuff like filtering out certain key words or phrases. I can, for example, filter out anything related to politics or written by Cory Doctorow. I can organise my feeds into folders - so if I want to avoid the news one day I can just skip that folder, or mark the whole thing read and pretend nothing happened that day. One of the biggest benefits for me is that I’m less likely to open my browser and get lost down the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Internet%20rabbit%20hole&#34;&gt;rabbit hole&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting started:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get started with RSS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up for an account with one of the many feed aggregators. Some of the more popular ones are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feedly.com&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsblur.com&#34;&gt;Newsblur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theoldreader.com&#34;&gt;The Old Reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inoreader.com/&#34;&gt;Inoreader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these have mobile applications - some have desktop companions too. I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/readkit/id588726889&#34;&gt;Readkit&lt;/a&gt; on OSX and &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/lire-rss-reader/id1531976425&#34;&gt;Lire&lt;/a&gt; on iOS. Many people like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reederapp.com/&#34;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt;. There are options for other operating systems, and the web applications don’t care what OS you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to some feeds. Most readers will automatically find the feed if you put in the address of the homepage. If you’re short of inspiration you could take a look at my &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamieadams.click/blogroll/&#34;&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel at your technical wizardry.&lt;/p&gt;
<hr />This is the full site feed. Too much stuff? Try one of the <a href="https://hinged.blog/feeds/">section feeds</a> instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
